Guide to the Phi Kappa Phi, University of Montana Chapter Records 1935-1974
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana-Missoula
Phi Kappa Phi, University of Montana Chapter Records
1954-1974
University of Montana-Missoula Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana—Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 867
Phi Kappa Phi. University of Montana Chapter
1.0 linear foot
Phi Kappa Phi is a scholastic honorary society that works to promote academic excellence in all fields of study in higher education. This collection contains the operational records of the University of Montana's chapter of Phi Kappa Phi in Missoula including correspondence, meeting minutes, membership information, by-laws, handbooks, awards, and publications.
Historical Note
Phi Kappa Phi is a scholastic honorary society founded in 1897 at the University of Maine. The Montana State University (now the University of Montana) chapter in Missoula was founded in 1954. The society involved itself with: raising funds for student scholarships; recognizing outstanding teachers and students at the university; inviting outside experts on various subject to speak on campus; and encouraging academic excellence in all disciplines.
The collection contains meeting minutes covering various society activites from 1965 to 1971. It also has a significant portion of correspondence that includes discussion of the creation of a chapter of Phi Kappa Phi at the University of Montana (then Montana State University), membership invitations, invitations for speakers at society/university sponsored events, correspondence among officers, and communication with the national office from the 1950s to the 1970s. There are also membership lists, bylaws, handbooks, awards materials, programs for events, and news releases from the 1960s and 1970s.
This collection is arranged first by material type and then chronologically.
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana-Missoula.
The custodial history of this collection is unknown.
There may be additions to this collection.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Phi Kappa Phi. University of Montana Chapter--Archives; University of Montana--Missoula--Societies, etc.; aUniversity of Montana--Missoula--Students--Societies, etc.
College students--Montana--Missoula--Societies, etc.
Colleges and Universities; Clubs and Societies; Montana
- Faculty Evaluation Materials for Awards, 1935-1965 (Box-folder 1/1)
- Petition to Phi Kappa Phi, March 1954 (Box-folder 1/2)
- Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 1/3)
- Register, 1954-1973 (Box-folder 1/4)
- Correspondence, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 1/5)
- News Releases and Clipping, 1963-1971 (Box-folder 1/6)
- Grizzly Guide, 1964 (Box-folder 1/7)
- Brain Bowl, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 1/8)
- Bylaws and Handbooks, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 1/9)
- Initiation, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 1/10)
- Meeting Minutes, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 1/11)
- Teacher of the Year, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 1/12)
- Membership, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 1/13)
- Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 2/1)
- National Office Pamphlets, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 2/2)
- Membership, Indexed, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 2/3)
- Outstanding Sophomore, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 2/4)
- Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 2/5)
- Outstanding Scholar Award, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 2/6)
- Correspondence, 1972 (Box-folder 2/7)
- Handbook, 1973 (Box-folder 2/8)
- Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 2/9)
- Miscellaneous Membership Materials, undated (Box-folder 2/10)